Erin M. Weiss

(307) 220-2006 | erin.michele.weiss@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Highly organized with strengths in analytical problem-solving and results-oriented planning with diverse background and experiences specializing in strategic development, data science, AI, machine learning, Python, R, retail, sales, marketing and communications, various energy-related disciplines, and China.

EDUCATION

William & Mary Raymond A. Mason School of Business, January 2023—August 2024

- Master of Science and Business Analytics (OMSBA); 4.0 GPA
- Member of Beta Gamma Sigma, an international honor society for business students

Georgetown University School of Foreign Service, August 2014 – May 2018

• Bachelor of Science, Major - Science, Technology, and International Affairs (STIA); Minor - Chinese; 3.44 GPA

Intensive Mandarin Study Abroad Program in Beijing, September 2016–December 2016

Associated Colleges China (ACC) Program in Beijing; Complete Mandarin immersion

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Python Tutor, July 2023 – Current

College of William & Mary

- Create lesson plans for graduate students taking the Python class in the OMSBA program
- Simplify complex subjects and topics into more digestible and understandable material
- Collaborate with the professor to refine the class through feedback
- Selected out of all the students immediately after taking the Python course due to my performance in class
- Obtained frequent positive feedback from students on my teaching abilities and help

Director of Strategic Planning, Feb 2020 – Nov 2022

Spirits & Spice

- Design and implement strategies to drive traffic and sales to the website and physical stores leading to 2x growth YoY on the website in just the first year
- Decide and manage marketing strategies including allocating budgets, having final say on initiatives, and keeping the team on the timeline
- Gather and analyze data to help forecast and plan key strategies for the whole company including: shipping costs, costs of goods, sales numbers, marketing, wages, rent, etc.
- Negotiate contracts for marketing, retail leasing, and contractors

Communications Coordinator, May 2018 - Feb 2020

Global Business Policy Council (GBPC), Kearney

- Crafted a comprehensive communications strategy with actionable ideas to better leverage the Council's research and reports
- Identified, created, and nurtured partnerships with journalists, commentators, content aggregators, key members of Kearney, and other thought leaders/think tank strategic alliances
- Created and managed timelines, deliverables, milestones, and development of communications strategy within the GBPC team
- Worked with the firm's web team to update the GBPC's corporate website, translating thought-leadership material into a web-relevant format

GPBC Summer Intern, Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

Kearney

Created and implemented a new social media strategy

Erin M. Weiss

(307) 220-2006 | erin.michele.weiss@gmail.com

- Created extensive 30–100-page research documents, PowerPoint slides, and Excel sheets to produce deliverables for clients in the GBPC.
- Researched a wide range of topics including: Middle-class in China, 3D Printing, neuroscience, supply chain management, international debt, Internet of Things, comprehensive research on India, scenario planning, and tax policy.

Intern, Jan 2017 - May 2017

Worldwatch Institute

- Supported the efforts of the Energy and Climate Committee
- Authored blogs on topics relating to energy efficiency and urban sprawl
- Contributed to grant proposal development
- Engaged in research to facilitate Worldwatch's projects, such as: African mini-grids, case studies, and a presentation to Caribbean states on renewable investments.

Intern, May 2016 - Aug 2016

Jackson Hole Center for Global Affairs

- Managed high-ranking Chinese officials from Shanxi Province during their time spent in Jackson/Yellowstone exploring a sister-city relationship
- Conducted research on a variety of topics including: National Security and Climate Change, Coal Transition Strategies, and Sister-Cities
- Co-wrote Transition Strategies for Carbon Intensive Economies Intern Article

Intern, Oct 2014 - May 2016

Georgetown University Energy Prize (GUEP)

- Analyzed energy efficiency and media information from the 52 communities in the \$5 million GUEP
- Conducted exploratory research in prize concepts relating to prizes and grants
- Collaborated to organize and run a major convention with the purpose of connecting 150 public sector leaders at the federal, state, and local levels to inspire, train, and develop more ambitious prize ideas.

Assistant Manager, Jun 2010 - Aug 2016

Pearls By Shari

- Produce high-end sales ranging \$10,000-\$100,000+
- Significant customer service interaction
- Order inventory
- Administrative support

SKILLS AND ACTIVITIES

- Strong skills in coding languages: R, Python, AI (TensorFlow, and Keras), Machine learning, PCA, Gurobi, Tableau, LaTex, Quarto, Markdown
- Familiar in HTML, CSS, GitHub, Bash/Shell
- Proficient in Mandarin: Passed
 Georgetown SFS Fluency Exam in Spring
 2018; Attained HSK Certification Level II,
 Fall 2014 after teaching myself Chinese in
 High School
- **Proficient in Microsoft Office:** Excel, Power Point (Gantt Charts, etc.), Word
- Proficient in Software: QuickBooks;
 Acumatica (ERP system); Shopify; ClickUp;
 Humanity
- Proficient in Marketing Tools: Facebook, Google, Twitter, LinkedIn, SEO, Attentive (SMS), Klaviyo, MailChimp, Eventbrite, Yelp, Google Ads
- College Extra Curriculars: After School Kids (A.S.K.) Volunteer, Smithsonian Volunteer